# Jeanne d'Arc NYIRAMWIZA

Full Stack Engineer (NodeJS and ReactJs) with 3+ years of experience. Strong ownership mindset, proficient in backend technologies, excellent communication and collaboration skills, and a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies.

jeannedarcnyiramwiza@gmail.com +250783451689 <u>LinkedIn</u> Github

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### KonectIn

#### Nigeria, Lagos (Remote)

## **Backend Engineer**

DEC 2023 - PRESENT

- Resolved backend errors in Resume builder platform, ensuring 100% issue resolution accuracy through rigorous testing with Supertest.
- Improved code architecture for better maintainability and scalability, integrating Mailtrap and AWS S3, and employing Swagger UI for API documentation.
- Eliminated bugs in the resume builder platform, boosting client trust and increasing website user engagement by 25% and system reliability by 30%.

#### **CoCreation Hub**

## Rwanda, Kigali (Hybrid)

## **Backend Engineer**

JUNE 2020 - FEB 2023

- Implemented a platform for interdisciplinary collaboration in epidemiological research, uniting 400+ professionals from diverse fields.
- Developed a digital health tool with therapy, self-help, and crisis intervention, leading to a mental health management improvement.
- Developed a platform for real-time social network analysis, leading to a 20% increase in interventions during the COVID-19 pandemic and saving lives.

#### Coding Black Females

#### **United Kingdom, London(Remote)**

## **React Course Instructor**

OCT 2022 - DEC 2022

- Crafted a transformative learning journey for students, regardless of their location or background.
- Offered guidance to a global audience, bridging geographical gaps to create an inclusive learning environment.
- Empowered diverse students in tech, leading to a 30% increase in career placements.

#### Coding Black Females

#### **United Kingdom, London(Remote)**

### **Teaching Assistant**

JUNE 2022 - OCT 2022

- Collaborated with the Introduction to the Web Development course instructor to create an engaging learning experience for students across 5 continents.
- Provided guidance and support to students, ensuring they had the resources they needed to succeed.
- Participated in discussions and offered valuable insights, contributing to the overall success of the course.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Event Management Tool Github**

 Employed TypeScript, Express, MySQL, Docker, Mocha, Chai, AWS S3, and GraphQL to develop an event management tool, streamlining planning and enhancing user experience.

#### Resume Builder Platform Github

• Utilized Node.js, MongoDB, AWS S3, Mailtrap, and Supertest to enhance a resume builder, improving system reliability, and integrating AWS S3 for file management.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

#### Stack

NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, NestJS, TypeORM,TypeDi

#### Other

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS (EC2, S3), Heroku, ElasticSearch, CI/CD,RESTful API, AWS, GraphQL, Docker, MySQL, Redis, Supertest,TypeORM,TypeDi

#### **LANGUAGES**

Kinyarwanda, native English C1, advanced French C2, Proficient

#### **EDUCATION**

**Azubi Africa**, Certificate (Front end Development)
Remote
2023 - 2024

Moringa School, Certificate (Web Development) Rwanda, Kigali 2018 - 2019

#### University of Rwanda,

Bachelors of Science (Agribusiness) Rwanda, Huye 2010 - 2013